<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="/The-Blissful-Mind/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/The-Blissful-Mind/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-14T02:12:31+03:00</updated><id>/The-Blissful-Mind/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Blissful Mind</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">how to stop talking yourself out of things</title><link href="/The-Blissful-Mind/how-to-stop-talking-yourself-out-of-things/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="how to stop talking yourself out of things" /><published>2019-07-26T11:57:53+03:00</published><updated>2019-07-26T11:57:53+03:00</updated><id>/The-Blissful-Mind/how-to-stop-talking-yourself-out-of-things</id><content type="html" xml:base="/The-Blissful-Mind/how-to-stop-talking-yourself-out-of-things/">&lt;p&gt;How many times have you come up with a brilliant idea for something only to psych yourself out of doing it? If you’re
  an overthinker or perfectionist, you probably talk yourself out of doing things on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you get all up in your head and convince yourself it’s no longer a good idea even though you were super excited
  about it before. Perhaps you pick apart your ideas and focus on what could go wrong instead of what could go right.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though it’s important to think things through and weigh the pros and cons, overthinking is often a form of
  procrastination that leads to inaction. In order to find success, you have to take imperfect action instead of living
  in your head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’m sharing the common reasons why we talk ourselves out of things, how that can sabotage your success,
  and ways you can take action instead of letting your ego get in the way. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why We Talk Ourselves Out Of Things&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest reasons you talk yourself out of things is because you think you don’t have the confidence to
  succeed. The keyword here is *think*. When you start to overanalyze your confidence levels, you pick apart the things
  about yourself that you’re not confident in. This only convinces you that you shouldn’t take action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also happens if you overthink things to death. When you go on tangents in your head until you’ve thought of all
  of the worst case scenarios, you start to fear the negative outcomes. But really, you’ve just created these negative
  outcomes in your own head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;When you continue this pattern of talking yourself out of things, you eventually make yourself believe
  that you’re
  not good enough to make changes in your life. You reignite that belief every time you decide to avoid or not do
  something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you worry what people will think of you if you don’t succeed. This takes the focus back to the negative outcome
  again which creates more resistance towards a positive outcome. People are going to think what they think of you
  regardless. They’ll either judge you because you messed up or they’ll judge you because you never made an effort to
  change. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;How To Stop Talking Yourself Out Of Things&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Don’t wait until you’re ready&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is power in planning, but planning often becomes a form of procrastination because you avoid doing the work. We
  plan because we want to feel prepared and ready, but there is really no such thing as feeling ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, you have to build your confidence by doing little things every day that take you out of your comfort zone.
  Whatever the big thing is that you want to do, break it down into smaller steps and push aside any self-sabotaging
  thoughts come up. Don’t let perfectionism or the need to be ready give you a reason to procrastinate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Work on your mindset&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above all else, you need a strong mindset in order to get out of your comfort zone. A strong mindset gives you the
  confidence to take action and helps you become aware of the moments when you’re sabotaging yourself. Create a mindset
  routine like this one that helps you cultivate healthy thoughts about yourself and focus on what you want to
  accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;question&quot;&gt;Question: What’s one thing you can take action on today?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this post has encouraged you to get out of your own head and believe in your own ideas. By doing things before
  you’re ready, working on your mindset, and holding yourself accountable, you’ll start to see big changes in your life.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ellie E.</name></author><summary type="html">How many times have you come up with a brilliant idea for something only to psych yourself out of doing it? If you’re an overthinker or perfectionist, you probably talk yourself out of doing things on a regular basis.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">the five key elements to a healthy mindset</title><link href="/The-Blissful-Mind/the-five-key-elements-to-a-healthy-mindset/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="the five key elements to a healthy mindset" /><published>2019-07-25T11:57:53+03:00</published><updated>2019-07-25T11:57:53+03:00</updated><id>/The-Blissful-Mind/the-five-key-elements-to-a-healthy-mindset</id><content type="html" xml:base="/The-Blissful-Mind/the-five-key-elements-to-a-healthy-mindset/">&lt;p&gt;When I was in college, I became obsessed with what I ate and how often I went to the gym. I would track everything
  that went into my mouth, and I felt guilty if I didn’t go to the gym every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though my body was healthy, my mind was a toxic place because I put unrealistic expectations on myself. One of the
  reasons why I write and coach about mindset work now is because I know that I am only as healthy as my mind is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more I’ve dug into mindset work, the more I’ve noticed certain patterns that hold us back when we’re trying to
  make changes in our lives. When our thoughts are unhealthy, we tend to succumb to insecurity, uncertainty, overwhelm,
  and worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’m sharing five key elements to work on in order to cultivate a healthy mindset. If you’re an
  overthinker, procrastinator, or perfectionist, this post is for you 🙌🏻&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What Is A Healthy Mindset?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A healthy mindset involves finding ways to grow from your thoughts instead of letting them control your life. Rather than dwelling on a negative thought until it becomes overwhelming, the healthy mindset tries to a) move beyond that thought or b) simply accept it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of obsessing over a positive mindset (I wrote about why you don’t need to do that in this post), we should focus on cultivating a healthy mindset. I say that because you can have a healthy mindset even if you feel negative sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;When you continue this pattern of talking yourself out of things, you eventually make yourself believe
  that you’re
  not good enough to make changes in your life. You reignite that belief every time you decide to avoid or not do
  something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After compiling as much information as I could from people who have shared their struggles with me (via email, DMs, comments, and coaching), I discovered a few patterns and tendencies when it comes to mindset setbacks. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;The 5 C’s Of A Healthy Mindset&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Calmness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to calm your mind when you’re under pressure is crucial to a healthy mindset. When your thoughts are all over the place, it’s difficult to see things as they really are. Calmness comes when you bring awareness to what’s happening and what you’re thinking. By figuring out go-to strategies and practices that calm your mind, you can center yourself and recognize when you’re overthinking or worrying about insignificant details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2. Clarity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a clear idea of what’s important to you is key to dealing with indecision. So much of our brain space gets taken up when we’re unsure of who we are and what we want. When you get clear on your priorities, goals, and values, you can remove the overwhelm that comes from uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3. Compassion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest contributors to an unhealthy mindset is a lack of compassion towards yourself. When you’re constantly comparing yourself to others, pressuring yourself to be perfect, and doubting your own abilities, you only sabotage your success. Compassion allows you to accept yourself, set healthy expectations, and trust yourself and the journey you’re on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4. Concentration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concentration is about commitment and dedication to yourself. We live in the age of distractions, which makes it all too easy to lose track of what’s important to you and even who you are. When you focus on what other people are doing instead of your own path, you get stuck. Focusing on what matters and making sacrifices with your time allows you to follow through and actually make progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;5. Courage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Courage helps us take action. When we procrastinate and avoid taking action, we keep ourselves stuck. Courage might sound like it’s about taking big, scary leaps into the unknown, but sometimes courage is as small as tackling a simple task you’ve been putting off. Courage allows us to take imperfect action, and that action helps us to build confidence, resiliency, and strength within ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;question&quot;&gt;Question: Which area of your mindset are you working on?&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Ellie E.</name></author><summary type="html">When I was in college, I became obsessed with what I ate and how often I went to the gym. I would track everything that went into my mouth, and I felt guilty if I didn’t go to the gym every day.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">how to deal with negative people</title><link href="/The-Blissful-Mind/how-to-deal-with-negative-people/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="how to deal with negative people" /><published>2019-07-24T11:57:53+03:00</published><updated>2019-07-24T11:57:53+03:00</updated><id>/The-Blissful-Mind/how-to-deal-with-negative-people</id><content type="html" xml:base="/The-Blissful-Mind/how-to-deal-with-negative-people/">&lt;p&gt;Does other people’s negative energy bring you down? Maybe it’s your coworkers, family members, or even friends you’ve grown apart from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re surrounded by negativity, it’s easy to absorb that energy and start to feel negative yourself. This can mess with your mindset and make you feel drained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why it’s so important to be around people who you easily connect with and who uplift your spirits. We all know that’s not always possible though, especially since we don’t get to choose our family members or coworkers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How Negativity Affects Us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve all dealt with negative, frustrated, and overbearing people in our lives. I remember working with someone who was in a state of panic. They were trying to figure something out at the last minute and were clearly frustrated that things weren’t going to plan. In turn, I was getting frustrated because they were being impatient and sassy towards me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quote that an old coworker used to say came to mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;“Lack of planning on your part does not constitute an emergency on mine.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever it is, you can feel yourself being affected when you’re around them. Most of us tend to absorb the mood of whoever’s around us, so how do we avoid letting negative people drain our energy when we can’t escape them? Here are a few tips to help:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How To Deal With Negative People&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Detach&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to calm your mind when you’re under pressure is crucial to a healthy mindset. When your thoughts are all over the place, it’s difficult to see things as they really are. Calmness comes when you bring awareness to what’s happening and what you’re thinking. By figuring out go-to strategies and practices that calm your mind, you can center yourself and recognize when you’re overthinking or worrying about insignificant details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2. Avoid Blame&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a clear idea of what’s important to you is key to dealing with indecision. So much of our brain space gets taken up when we’re unsure of who we are and what we want. When you get clear on your priorities, goals, and values, you can remove the overwhelm that comes from uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3. Respond Calmly&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest contributors to an unhealthy mindset is a lack of compassion towards yourself. When you’re constantly comparing yourself to others, pressuring yourself to be perfect, and doubting your own abilities, you only sabotage your success. Compassion allows you to accept yourself, set healthy expectations, and trust yourself and the journey you’re on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4. Be Firm&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concentration is about commitment and dedication to yourself. We live in the age of distractions, which makes it all too easy to lose track of what’s important to you and even who you are. When you focus on what other people are doing instead of your own path, you get stuck. Focusing on what matters and making sacrifices with your time allows you to follow through and actually make progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;5. Find The Positive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Courage helps us take action. When we procrastinate and avoid taking action, we keep ourselves stuck. Courage might sound like it’s about taking big, scary leaps into the unknown, but sometimes courage is as small as tackling a simple task you’ve been putting off. Courage allows us to take imperfect action, and that action helps us to build confidence, resiliency, and strength within ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;question&quot;&gt;Question: How do you deal with negative people?&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this post has given you some tips to handle negative energy when it comes your way. If you can find ways to stay calm and protect your own energy, you can avoid letting negativity affect you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ellie E.</name></author><summary type="html">Does other people’s negative energy bring you down? Maybe it’s your coworkers, family members, or even friends you’ve grown apart from.</summary></entry></feed>